Mattia Fiorio Software engineer

CONTACTS

E-mail:

mtt.fiorio.jobs@gmail.com

Website:

matfio.com

Location:

Copenhagen, Denmark

SKILLS

JavaScript/Typescript, HTML/CSS, C#, .NET, NodeJS, Python/PySpark

React, Jest, Selenium, Playwright, Storybook

MySQL, MS SQL Server, Snowflake, Amazon Redshift

Unity

Agile Scrum, Jira

Git, GitHub

SUMMARY

I have been a Software Developer for over 9 years and currently work for a leading publishing organization. I am skilled in JavaScript/Typescript, C#, Python and SQL.

I have worked with web front-end development using the latest web technologies, videogames development using Unity as game engine and handled big data pipelines.

In addition to my skills in coding, I am skilled in conducting technical analysis as well as assisting teams in project management and agile frameworks implementation.

EXPERIENCES

2020 - present

< FRONT END DEVELOPER | Clio | CPH

Developing and testing frontend components, while also managing the team backlog and output, scrum rituals and communication with stakeholders

- Releasing the product on time for future iterations based on user feedback by pruning and prioritizing the product backlog with input from stakeholders and the rest of the development teams.
- Improving programmers output by promoting and implementing agile methodologies. Taking an active role as facilitator during agile rituals.
- Creating and updating the newest version of Clio's SaaS e-learning platform which was used by 90% of schools in Denmark before being acquired by L&R Uddannelse, through the usage of React components. These components were developed in isolation using story book, React hooks while following SOLID principles and unit testing with Jest.
- Implementing E2E tests using Selenium (Java) and Playwright.
- Cutting down releasing times by 40% by extending and refactoring existing GitHub actions to leverage reusable workflows and parallel execution.

< SOFTWARE ENGINEER | MovieStarPlanet | CPH 2

2013 - 2020

Created in-game features and simplified the development through the creation of tools and frameworks, handled analytics pipelines

- Streamlined the creation of games by developing a company-wide framework based on Unity that provided plug and play elements to the other game teams.
- Developed in-game features for a massively multiplayer game with more than 100 million users split between web browsers, android and iOS devices. Development was done within an agile scrum team. Example of features are: player-to-player communication through a NodeJS server, in-game shops with reusable dynamic scrollable lists, etc.

LANGUAGES

English: fluent written and

spoken

Italian: native Danish: basic

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

In my spare time, I enjoy running to challenge my physical limits. I also enjoy travelling, socializing, reading and playing games with friends and family.

Currently I am frequenting Danish classes in order to be able to communicate more efficiently.

- Coded back-end robust and optimized C# .NET functionalities to retrieve and save data to SQL databases and to support game features with particular attention to possible security breaches.
- Implemented several UI and usability improvements to the user experience while working closely with game designers .
- Boosted productivity by drastically reducing time spent on marketing and support tasks by introducing tools for batch management of data and unification of publishing functionalities across all different game domains. The tools were created using ASP.NET with iterative customeroriented development approach.
- Developed the analytics pipeline while cooperating with external companies. The pipeline handled 50+ million events per day which were archived into the Snowflake warehouse and processed through Databricks (PySpark) procedures. Presented and taught the architecture to other engineers.

EDUCATION

< MSc Video Games Technology | ITU Copenhagen

2012 - 2014

Study specialization in designing and developing videogames and videogames engines. Coursework included:

- Coursework of data mining, design, game engines, game development.
 Successfully developed various games in different roles: designer,
 programmer and project manager.
- Participated as a programmer in The National Academy of Digital and Interactive Entertainment (DADIU). Developed and released a full game on Google Play Store.

< BSc in IT Engineering | Politecnico di Milano

2008 - 2011

Coursework included:

• Coursework of software engineering, databases and web, computer architectures, robotics, communication science and knowledge engineering.